<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Shalini Chaudhary</title>
    <link href="https://soigne68.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://soigne68.github.io" />
    <updated>2021-10-06T16:15:15+05:30</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Shalini Chaudhary</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://soigne68.github.io</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Show gratitude in all your actions!</title>
        <author>
            <name>Shalini Chaudhary</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://soigne68.github.io/show-gratitude-in-all-your-actions.html"/>
        <id>https://soigne68.github.io/show-gratitude-in-all-your-actions.html</id>

        <updated>2021-10-06T16:15:15+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    "Acknowledging the good that you already have in your life is the foundation for all abundance." I strongly believe in this quote because being thankful for what we have paves the way for more to come. Practicing this turns the excruciating pain of difficult times&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><em><strong>"Acknowledging the good that you already have in your life is the foundation for all abundance."</strong></em></p>
<p>I strongly believe in this quote because being thankful for what we have paves the way for more to come. Practicing this turns the excruciating pain of difficult times into tolerable ones. We shouldn't be deterred by the unfavourable events taking place in our lives, as these events only bring out our real resilient self into full projection. Even if the things are going wrong, set your vibrations into the tuning mode of your choice and see the difference. I know for a fact that it's easy said being done. But believe me, once you practice this art, you will find a different meaning to your life. </p>
<p>Let me give you a quick example. Around a decade ago, there came a night that seemed to loom larger then my existence. I was left devastated, broken and shattered by circumstances. I had my children with me and that was the only sunshine in the otherwise pitch dark scenario. I thanked God for what I had and tried to move on. I won't lie. I did cry in the initial phase but time is a great healer. It taught me that the  universe aligns us with people, things and situations. If there is something that is not required in our life, universe conspires to throw it out of the system. It may take time but it will definitely work for our betterment. Today, when I look back, I thank God for chartering this path for me. I bow my head in complete reverence to Him for blessing me with two mature individuals as my children. What troubled me didn't vanish suddenly, but I moved out of my tunnel vision of looking at things and tried to broaden my horizon into the periphery of my life where amazing things were happening in different manners.  We only need to arrange or orchestrate the things for desired results. There comes a time when you realise that everything that you've gone through was actually a blessing in disguise.</p>
<p>When we are building ourselves for a better tomorrow, there shouldn't be any time to dwell on the small little things actually petty things of yesterday. Make gratitude a fundamental feature of your existence. Right in the morning when you open your eyes, thank God for blessing you with a new day and promise yourself to do the best you can to make the day a remarkable one. When you sleep at night thank all those people in your heart, who helped you to achieve your goals during the day. It's a very healing exercise. If you can thank people in person, don't lose the chance. You never know you may not get the opportunity again. There goes a story about a man whose life was saved only because he had the habit of thanking the security guard before leaving for the day. One day he was locked in his office and couldn't reach anyone for help. The security guard raised an alarm about it because he hadn't seen him going and saved his life. </p>
<p>Every person is struggling his or her own battle. We should try to be kind and generous in all our ways and means. As we navigate the highs and lows in life, the love and compassion we share with others gives the direction and brightness to life. Let this journey be a journey of healing and make this world a better place to live. I thank you all for being there with me.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Change is inevitable</title>
        <author>
            <name>Shalini Chaudhary</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://soigne68.github.io/change-is-inevitable.html"/>
        <id>https://soigne68.github.io/change-is-inevitable.html</id>

        <updated>2021-07-04T21:45:03+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    There are times when we don't want to risk change in our otherwise comfortable lifestyles. We strive hard to remain in our comfort zone and resist all changes. As a result, our growth doesn't reach to its full bloom. We condition ourselves to a stagnant&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>There are times when we don't want to risk change in our otherwise comfortable lifestyles. We strive hard to remain in our comfort zone and resist all changes. As a result, our growth doesn't reach to its full bloom. We condition ourselves to a stagnant life  and as a consequence live a life like the Dead Sea. The Sea of Galilee also receives the water from the same source (Jordan river), but is resplendent with flourishing flora and fauna, only because it allows the water to come and go. On the other hand the Dead Sea retains the water and ultimately annihilates all chances of life. The most important feature that we need to understand is that change brings a new sunshine everywhere. Nature is the best example here.</p>
<p>These changes, whether internal/external teach us something new. Most of the times external changes propel us to make a shift in the internal programming, which inturn brings a change in our behaviour, our thinking and reacting to any situation. For personal growth, it's important to bring voluntary changes in our lives, by embracing new challenges with resilience and power. To become a better version of ourselves, we must work internally like the Chinese Bamboo (which takes years to show the first sign of life, but when it does, it dazzles the whole world with its phenomenal growth).</p>
<p>As a human being, we get anxious with change. And it's quite natural too, because we have been wired like this from the starting. I am not suggesting that we should change everything, but we must give sometime to ourselves and ask-Where do I want to be five/ten years down the line? If the answer is different from your your current lifestyle then gear up to change because merely wishing won't manifest the desire into reality. Set up a long term goal and break it into small achievable goals and then work with patience and persistence to achieve them with panache. </p>
<p>Set your principles in tune with your goals to guide you better. You don't know how something will turn out when you act, but you do know whether this action is in line with your principles or not. Show strength in dealing with whatever outcome and you will find yourself in a better position. For example, some of my guiding principles are to become an entrepreneur, travel worldwide, to read and write extensively, build trust and create a better society. To achieve these, I had to make some changes in my thought process. Leaving a regular job with a regular paycheck is risky but liberating and profound. I have committed to myself to achieve all these goals in this lifetime only.</p>
<p>Being true and honest, to one's own self is very important to reach the desired position. At times, we don't know the nuances of many things. Be a learner there, instead of diving headfirst in the unknown waters. Update your skills, have faith and be the CHANGE. </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Life is a canvas!</title>
        <author>
            <name>Shalini Chaudhary</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://soigne68.github.io/life-is-a-canvas.html"/>
        <id>https://soigne68.github.io/life-is-a-canvas.html</id>

        <updated>2021-07-04T21:38:07+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    This Holi, let's all resolve to fill our life with myriad colours. It's in our hands that we paint the canvas of our lives with colours of positivity or the other way round. Colours radiate with dazzling shine when they emanate from the heart. Nature&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>This Holi, let's all resolve to fill our life with myriad colours. It's in our hands that we paint the canvas of our lives with colours of positivity or the other way round. Colours radiate with dazzling shine when they emanate from the heart. Nature teaches us the beauty of each colour. The rising sun with its orange colour gives warmth and then it's bright yellow colour promises happiness, hope and cheer. It brightens up each and every corner of the earth. The vast sky with it's blue colour gives us peace and calmness. It sends a message that there is no end to posibilities. We only have to set our eyes on our goal and work persistently. Red colour radiates love in all it's forms. The beautiful red rose mesmerises us with it's beauty and fragrance and even when you pluck it, it won't lose it's beauty. Purple colour motivates us to be kind and compassionate and so on...</p>
<p>The best part is that we have all this in our lives without any prejudice. I feel, we can use this abundance not only to beautify our own life but also to give meaning to our existence. This precious lifetime has more significance, if we impact other lives. Knowingly or unknowingly, we leave a mark on others. Let that be a remarkable one. At times, a small gesture of giving a smile to somebody changes the life course of that person. May be that person required just a reassuring smile to move on. Be that angel in the lives of others. You can make the difference. Life may not be very happening all the time, but remaining grumpy won't solve the problem. You have to move on and see the bright side. There are positives in negatives too. I remember a story that I had read some time back, which talks about a mother and her daughter. The mother was bogged down by the amount of work that she had to do and the daughter was doing her homework of writing a paragraph on "Negative Thanks Giving". The girl was writing about the things, which didn't please her initially but had a rewarding ending. Like the bad medicine which tasted bitter but cured her from the ailment or the final exams which meant holidays are round the corner. The lady could understand that, this amount of work means she has a shelter to live in and people in her life to look after and her whole mind set was changed. We should look at the better part of life and make every day a great day. Why not to make this life a life of gratitude? Because, it will unlock the magnificence of life.   </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Adventure is just a moment away!</title>
        <author>
            <name>Shalini Chaudhary</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://soigne68.github.io/adventure-is-just-a-moment-away-3.html"/>
        <id>https://soigne68.github.io/adventure-is-just-a-moment-away-3.html</id>

        <updated>2021-07-04T21:48:57+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    It took me a little longer to get back to my routine of writing posts, as promised, but I was on a journey...an adventurous journey with Bilbo Baggins. It has reiterated my conviction that, "The world is not in your books and maps. It's out&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>It took me a little longer to get back to my routine of writing posts, as promised, but I was on a journey...an adventurous journey with Bilbo Baggins. It has reiterated my conviction that, "The world is not in your books and maps. It's out there". We need to have that spirit of moving out from our comfort zone and explore the unknown.</p>
<p>This journey started with my picking the book "The Hobbit" by J.R.R. Tolkiens. It's a fantasy novel for children and when I laid my hands on it, I was wondering about the experience. I was not sure about it's completion. It all started with a doubt and a light hearted desire to read a novel for children, which had won acclaim all over the world. It was indeed an unforgettable journey. The main character- Bilbo Baggins, is presented as the most complacent creature, living a pretty average life in his hole. But once he was challenged for an adventure and the way he fought with Smaug (dragon) single handedly to reclaim the lost treasure, it simply projects him as the real hero. We can't say that he reclaimed his lost power, because he got the power which he didn't know he had. He was in complete amazement with himself because slaying the huge spider or fighting with the slimy Gollum without the help of Gandalf (wizard) or dwarves was a nightmare for him. He realized that - Happiness lies in knowing our worth. The fiercer and bolder Hobbit found a new meaning to life.</p>
<p>It cemented my belief that the ability to take action in the face of fear is the most crucial thing. Rest happens automatically. Once you win the battle with your mind then no force can stop you to scale greater heights. Most of the times we are slaves to our own inhibitions and don't allow ourselves to step out and take the challenge. What is most important in life is the faith in our abilities. We live in a society where most of the times,  our roles are pre-defined and we also believe in our limited capacity. We just have to break free the shackles and build a new pesona. President Roosevelt's words are very apt to quote here," The only thing we have to fear is...fear itself - nameless, unreasoning, unjustified terror which paralyzes needed efforts to convert retreat into advance".</p>
<p>There is one more instance where Tolkien has truly presented a great idea. It was when Gandalf along with Thorin and company (dwarves) persuaded Baggins for the adventure.</p>
<p>Baggins asked,"<em><strong>You can promise that I'll come back?</strong></em>"</p>
<p>And Gandalf answered, <em><strong>"No. And if you do, you'll not be the same."</strong></em></p>
<p>What a beautiful interpretation! It actually stirs a positive thought process. And yes, it proved right, because Baggins was a changed creature after the sinister fight. He had shown extreme mental fortitude when he gave the Arkenstone (Stone which gives you the infinite powers) to the army of men and elves instead of his comrades, so that the damaging war and bloodshed can be avoided. Later on risking his own safety, he returned to his people with a deep loyalty. His transformation from a shy and timid creature to a true hero is a classic example of fighting your own battles. </p>
<p>I recommend this book to those who can appreciate the subtleness of ideas. The dialogues are comical and hilarious at times, targetting the readers for whom it was originally written, but they do add to the overall beauty of the book.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>All The Light We Cannot See</title>
        <author>
            <name>Shalini Chaudhary</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://soigne68.github.io/all-the-light-we-cannot-see.html"/>
        <id>https://soigne68.github.io/all-the-light-we-cannot-see.html</id>

        <updated>2020-10-25T08:36:07+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    There comes a time in life when we are blinded by the outer light and completely merge with the system of extravaganza. We start believing that to be the truth of life and expect no escape. We don't even feel that something is missing and&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>There comes a time in life when we are blinded by the outer light and completely merge with the system of extravaganza. We start believing that to be the truth of life and expect no escape. We don't even feel that something is missing and some concrete action is required to bring in the much needed change. Constant pressure of work, life, relationships, society and what not... is being harped upon in a continuous process. And we don't even realize the light within, which has the ultimate power to transmute the mundane into magical.</p>
<p>This was the scenario of my life also around four months back. When I was a self proclaimed victim of extreme work and pressure. But, since the day I have actively started reading books...once again...I find a tremendous change in the thought process. There seems to be a complete overhaul of the system. And, mind you, it feels good. The words of Francis Bacon resound in my mind and I quote,'Reading maketh a full man; conference a ready man; and writing an exact man". This world of books has given a new perspective to life. Recently, I have read the book, All the light We Cannot See, by Anthony Doerr and it has completely changed my idea about blind people. Marie Laure, the main character of the story is blind, but the way she persevers and sustains in life is mind boggling. Her blindness never impedes her way to achieve excellence. The words, <em>Open your eyes and see what you can with them before they close forever,</em> have left an everlastng impression on me. It's true that it doesn't matter how many resources we have unless and until we know how to use them. Time is a very crucial thing and it goes without saying that once you lose hold of it, it almost gets impossible to catch the strings. Another character of the story, Werner, is an exceptionally intelligent boy with mechanical, technical and scientific knowledge. He was an orphan but his fascination to see the invisible waves took him to places. There is such a realistic presentation of the brutality of Nazi's and the traumatic experience of fleeing to other countries for peace, that at times it leaves you in pieces. </p>
<p>I could feel the light within each word and each expression of the book. Anthony Doerr has certainly found a place in  the list of my favourite writers. While reading the book, there were times, when I caught myself just staring at the words and drowning in the memories of my visit to Auschwitz {Krakow, Poland), where I could see the gas chambers and the depth of brutality by Hitler Army. </p>
<p>Now, that I am reading a book/week, I will put my reviews here, so that my readers may also get interested to delve deeper into the world of books.</p>
<p>It's a beautiful world. Let's weave each day with good ideas, plan each move for betterment and see the light within!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Setting Priorities</title>
        <author>
            <name>Shalini Chaudhary</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://soigne68.github.io/setting-priorities.html"/>
        <id>https://soigne68.github.io/setting-priorities.html</id>

        <updated>2020-08-22T20:58:41+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    We all wish to succeed and leave a mark in the pages of history, but don't plan a winning strategy for the same. As we move on in life, we come across varied experiences and find that one of the biggest challenges in life is&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>We all wish to succeed and leave a mark in the pages of history, but don't plan a winning strategy for the same. As we move on in life, we come across varied experiences and find that one of the biggest challenges in life is to become comfortable in uncomfortable situations. You step into your greatness only when you decide to step out of your comfort zone. Going by the flow and letting things happen to you will result in anaverage life. It's for us to decide what kind of life we envisage for ourselves.</p>
<p>I feel, that if our life goal is clear, then we won't have any regrets on the day of judgement. We must understand what we actually require and what requires to be left behind. As soon as we have the clarity of purpose, life will get its meaning. Life has precisely the meaning that we give to it.</p>
<p>Our priority in life should be to ensure our happiness in our being. Never feel depressed about what people say about you. If you are true to yourself, believe in your actions and can feel proud by the end of the day, then it doesn't matter what people say about you. Take the charge of your life and be successful.</p>
<p> Don't sit on the comforting couch basking in the glory of your achievements. Each day is a challenge and we must prove our mettle through perseverance. If one fine day, we feel that life is all settled and we need not work hard to improve then it's nothing less then the murder of our better version. We fear changes because they shake our comfort but actually these changes are instrumental in our growth. These days of Covid-19 have taught this to us in the most effective manner. We had never thought of this system of online education and initially there were lot of hiccups and bumpy roads. But now everything has come to a new normal. Old ways don't open new doors. We should be confident to take the risk or lose the chance. </p>
<p>At times, we learn this lesson the hard way. It's when we lose the opportunity that we grumble over its loss. Take the life by its reins. You are the master of your fate, and the captain of your soul.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>It&#x27;s a mind game!</title>
        <author>
            <name>Shalini Chaudhary</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://soigne68.github.io/thought-process.html"/>
        <id>https://soigne68.github.io/thought-process.html</id>

        <updated>2021-07-04T21:46:27+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    There have been numerous talk shows/webinars these days on developing the skills to sustain hard times. All over the country, people have started talking about the importance of mental health and I feel that is a welcome move. People have come to understand that you&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>There have been numerous talk shows/webinars these days on developing the skills to sustain hard times. All over the country, people have started talking about the importance of mental health and I feel that is a welcome move. People have come to understand that you are no lesser a human being, if you take expert help to come out of your emotional problems. It's no more a taboo to talk about it. In this time of global pandemic, anxiety, loneliness and frustration are common everywhere, but we have to be ultimate survivors AND WE WILL BE. We have to look for solutions. Problems evolve us as human beings and push us towards a better version of ourselves. What is important in life is that, how we deal with them? What is the meaning we are giving to the problem? If we bow down and surrender, it will grow exponentially and soon we will be the victim of self-sabotage. Each and every thing that we possess can be taken away from us, but our real treasure--our power of thinking and decision making can not be snatched. Even if things go to ashes, and there seems no hope of revival...we can rise from the dust, just like the mythological phoenix. We can bring a paradigm shift in the existing scenario by trying to create positive vibes...first within ourselves and then spreading it in the society at large. </p>
<p>If we wish to achieve someting in our life. then nothing can deter us. We need to invest our time, mind and energy. We need to train our belief system, because belief shapes our behaviour and behaviour makes the destiny. Be in the company of enthusiastic people, who speak good, practice good and sprinkle the charm of their goodness everywhere. I had read a book (Man's search for meaning) by Dr Viktor Frankl, where he has enumerated the various hardships he had to face in the Nazi concentration camp, during the World War II. He was resilient and visualised a better tomorrow. And he did survive to tell his part of the success story to the world. There are other examples also, where we find exceptional courage and determination to excel. Mountaineer Arunima Sinha is the most glaring example. She was lying on the railway track for the whole night in the most deplorable condition, but her determination was stronger then the problems, and inspite of being amputated below the knee and having a prosthetic leg, she achieved her dream of hoisting national flag on Mount Everest. When people can come out from such dire situations, then it's not difficult for us too. We just have to maintain hygiene, keep social distance and remain at home. This shall also pass.</p>
<p>I have realised that there are unlimited possibilities to recreate, reinvent and reenergise ourselves in this Lockdown period. All we have to do is to decide for a better tomorrow. Take this time as a time to put reset button. I feel that if we have the half glass full attitude, then we we will be able to sail through all odds. Don't feel scared with the magnanimity of the problem, rather face it head on and I am sure you will succeed. Be confident about yourself, plan and priortise your goals, set a timeline and work towards it. There cannot be any force stopping you to achieve your dreams.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>A tiny step  </title>
        <author>
            <name>Shalini Chaudhary</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://soigne68.github.io/a-tiny-step.html"/>
        <id>https://soigne68.github.io/a-tiny-step.html</id>

        <updated>2021-07-04T21:45:40+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    The journey of a thousand miles begins with a single step, and here I am, taking a tiny step towards the fulfilment of my long cherished dream of writing a blog. I was busy in the humdrum of life and found no time suitable to&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>The journey of a thousand miles begins with a single step, and here I am, taking a tiny step towards the fulfilment of my long cherished dream of writing a blog.</p>
<p>I was busy in the humdrum of life and found no time suitable to pursue my dreams. These days, due to COVID-19 outbreak, life has come to a standstill.This time has forcibly taught us the importance of things that we had taken for granted. Family relations were dying down, the rich were getting richer and the life of poor was going down the drain. Now, this tiny virus has shown its might and told us that we are just a speck of dust in the hands of nature. Nature views us all with the same glass.</p>
<p>True, we are at home, just blocked from the outside world. But, isn't it beautiful? A magnificent realization has dawned upon us. All  hatred and spite has been shown the door and we are trying to be as productive, as we can, in these trying times. As parents and teachers, we are struggling hard to provide the best education to our children. We have come out from the belief that learning requires a pre-designated place called school/college, and can happen at home also. Constantly, I am receiving messages from parents showing their contentment in being an active participant in their child's education, They are realising the importance of schools and the plethora of activities that take place there, for the holistic development of their children. I feel the understanding between parents and teachers will improve exponentially.</p>
<p>Time to time, we are getting messages from various sectors, telling us the ways and means to utilise the time productively. Many online courses are free of charge during this 'Lock down period'. We must understand that education is not merely subject knowledge. It also requires practical hands on experience to deal with real life issues. Children should be taught basic culinary skills, plumbing, cleaning and dusting etc.  This time shall pass, but God forbid, if something like this happens again, at least we will be better prepared. We must learn from the lessons that it has taught. Quite unexpectedly, this tiny virus has taken over the mankind in the most brutal manner. Hundreds and thousands of people are dying but many more are surviving also. Let's all be very resilient and strong, within ourselves, and pledge to come out victorious from this 21 day isolation period.</p>
<p>This inconvenient time can be called as a 'golden chance' to visit the forgotten era and bring out the pearls from the recesses of time.This is the time to go with in, meditate and introspect and try to heal the battered soul. With social distancing, we can unite with ourselves, with people who should matter the most in our lives(referring to family members) and can plan for a better tomorrow. Everyone had been running around to amass more and more materialistic pleasures not only for themselves but for generations to come, as if they would be mutants and incompetent to feed for themselves.</p>
<p>There should be an end to all this. The world is a beautiful plce to live in. Let's all take a vow to give more quality time to our family members, protect each other and the Mother Earth for a better tomorrow. Let's imbibe gratitude to be our way of life and thank all those who are tirelessly working, so that we may live in peace. My salute to all the health officials, police department, emergency services personnel, and many unsung heroes without whom, it would have been a nightmare.</p>
<p>This being my first post, I would like to specially mention and thank my son, Abhishek, who created this platform for me, and my daughter, Aditi, who was a constant support to me. Without their contribution, my dream would not have seen the light of the day. </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
