<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Shalini Chaudhary</title>
    <link href="https://soigne68.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://soigne68.github.io" />
    <updated>2022-03-07T14:43:32+05:30</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Shalini Chaudhary</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://soigne68.github.io</id>

    <entry>
        <title>True happiness!</title>
        <author>
            <name>Shalini Chaudhary</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://soigne68.github.io/true-happiness.html"/>
        <id>https://soigne68.github.io/true-happiness.html</id>

        <updated>2022-03-07T14:43:32+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Happiness has different meanings for different people. Just like the sunrise and sunset kind of happiness. All of us can be happy if we centralise the core happiness within ourselves. There was a time that I was so naive that my happiness used to depend&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Happiness has different meanings for different people. Just like the sunrise and sunset kind of happiness. All of us can be happy if we centralise the core happiness within ourselves. There was a time that I was so naive that my happiness used to depend on the approval of others. Almost four decades of my life passed in this manner and then I realized that I had given undue importance to others. Slowly and gradually I picked up the pieces of my broken personality and tried to create a new 'me'. Now, I don't look for situations to make me happy. Rather I create my own happiness in my own way and have realized that this is the only way to be. No one should be given the authority to decide your happiness. Find happiness in yourself, in the things that make you happy, leave you contented. You will find that things have suddenly changed for better in your life. Try to remain receptive to what makes you feel happy and trust the process. You will surely reap benefits of your faith.</p>
<p>As born in a traditional family with 'zero to none' exposure to the outside world, it won't be an exaggeration to say that I knew nothing about the world. My childhood was laced with the proposition that people should be happy with you. Now, this was the major thing that shaped my personality. Being the youngest in the family, I always thought I must please my siblings, I must be good to my parents(which one should), I must make our guests feel at home and so on. You can very well understand that a child won't get any individuality or confidence in such circumstances. I tried to give my best in education and did my graduation with distinction. Now, came the time for post graduation and I was not allowed to go for a subject of my choice(as it was not available in my city). Well, being a subservient person, I followed what came to me. Adding more to the situation, I was married in the second semester of my further education. A new family, new people to deal with. I could have changed to a person who is aware of her requirements but as 'old habits die hard', I was the same in my new environment. And it had its toll on me in the best possible manner(ironically). I somehow completed my post graduation, did the degree course for teaching and started my career as a teacher. But then, God had His own designs and suddenly I was out of the 'Catch-22' situation and left to my own measures. To cut the long story short, I then chose the path which I had always in my mind and here I am with the first hand experience of the after effects of giving too much power and importance to others in your life.</p>
<p>The reason behind sharing my story is to bring home the clarity to my readers that it's your life. Take the reins in your hands and see the difference that you can make in your life. Loosen your attachments to the people around you, and you will naturally feel more connected to the person inside you. It's very important that we realise (sooner the better) the importance of being your own well-wisher first. In India, this realization is very important for the females, as they are taught to be tolerant, submissive and second to their counter-parts right from their early childhood. Knowing the pain of this, I try to give this understanding to all my acquaintances that no one is big or small. Both the genders have the equal right to carve a niche for themselves. The key to being happy is to know what to let go and what to accept in your life. It's a direction to your life not a destination. </p>
<p>I always practice gratitude, exercise, meditate and help others. This has helped me to move closer to my goal and find true happiness within myself. Planning a trip and spending quality time with family gives immense happiness.My recent trip to Mumbai and Jodhpur is a testament to this.</p>
<p> </p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/14/8FBF4D45-00A1-4FA3-832B-2B036BE2BA85.jpeg" sizes="(min-width: 61.3125em) 50vw, 100vw" srcset="https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/14/responsive/8FBF4D45-00A1-4FA3-832B-2B036BE2BA85-xs.jpeg 300w ,https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/14/responsive/8FBF4D45-00A1-4FA3-832B-2B036BE2BA85-sm.jpeg 480w ,https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/14/responsive/8FBF4D45-00A1-4FA3-832B-2B036BE2BA85-md.jpeg 768w"  alt="" width="323" height="404"></figure> <figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/14/90F8883E-8AB5-47D8-95D6-3B2EF322304E.jpeg" sizes="(min-width: 61.3125em) 50vw, 100vw" srcset="https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/14/responsive/90F8883E-8AB5-47D8-95D6-3B2EF322304E-xs.jpeg 300w ,https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/14/responsive/90F8883E-8AB5-47D8-95D6-3B2EF322304E-sm.jpeg 480w ,https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/14/responsive/90F8883E-8AB5-47D8-95D6-3B2EF322304E-md.jpeg 768w"  alt="" width="323" height="403"></figure>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/14/B564D115-424F-4D3A-AAAE-7228B3E934AF-4.heic" alt=""></figure><figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  style="color: var(--text-editor-body-color); font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);" src="https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/14/0354890E-DAC5-4AF0-B90E-4A13D22493C8.jpeg" sizes="(min-width: 61.3125em) 50vw, 100vw" srcset="https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/14/responsive/0354890E-DAC5-4AF0-B90E-4A13D22493C8-xs.jpeg 300w ,https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/14/responsive/0354890E-DAC5-4AF0-B90E-4A13D22493C8-sm.jpeg 480w ,https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/14/responsive/0354890E-DAC5-4AF0-B90E-4A13D22493C8-md.jpeg 768w"  alt="" width="324" height="431"></figure><figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  style="color: var(--text-editor-body-color); font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);" src="https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/14/B7E92574-8928-4A5E-ACAC-8AD589867A55.jpeg" sizes="(min-width: 61.3125em) 50vw, 100vw" srcset="https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/14/responsive/B7E92574-8928-4A5E-ACAC-8AD589867A55-xs.jpeg 300w ,https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/14/responsive/B7E92574-8928-4A5E-ACAC-8AD589867A55-sm.jpeg 480w ,https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/14/responsive/B7E92574-8928-4A5E-ACAC-8AD589867A55-md.jpeg 768w"  alt="" width="323" height="431"></figure>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>About Shalini</title>
        <author>
            <name>Shalini Chaudhary</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://soigne68.github.io/about-shalini.html"/>
        <id>https://soigne68.github.io/about-shalini.html</id>

        <updated>2022-03-04T08:17:15+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    With a career spanning more than two decades, Shalini has touched the lives of thousands of students and hundreds of teachers in her quest to uplift and improve the quality of life of her community through education. Whether it be through her early days as&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With a career spanning more than two decades, Shalini has touched the lives of thousands of students and hundreds of teachers in her quest to uplift and improve the quality of life of her community through education. Whether it be through her early days as a junior teacher, her rise through TGT and PGT certifications, her role as a vice principal or a principal, she truly embodies the spirit of the word “educationist”. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Today, she runs her latest initiative, ‘Academia’ - an attempt to bring world class English education to Haryana.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Until 2021, she headed one of the fastest growing educational institutions in Indus Public School in Hisar. After being brought in to spearhead the school’s ambitious vision for a turnaround in fortunes, she managed to not only stabilize the ship but also created a platform for it to thrive. Through an inspired combination of training, outreach programs, and general management, she managed to increase the student body by 80% over just her first six months. A fervent proponent of adopting the latest technologies, she evangelized adoption of Information and Communication Technology, a UNESCO recommendation, in the classroom. Under her leadership, Indus Public School has been recognized as one of the top digitally enabled schools in the country. A national-level athlete for Haryana herself, she has also managed to instill in her students a love for the outdoors. With her diligent tutelage, multiple children from the school have been selected for national level games. Her focus on teaching her cohort about sustainable living led her to working with the state government on tree planting initiatives and environmental preservation focused workshops at the school. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the past, she was chosen to establish the Hisar branch of the Presidium group of schools from the ground up. In her 3 years at the institution as a vice principal and acting-principal, she was responsible for designing and overseeing all teaching and support operations within the organization – from hiring staff to parent outreach, from financial management to social footprint and marketing. Taking the school from an empty building to a thriving campus with nearly 1000 students and a staff of more than 100, she managed to make Presidium a top choice for families in the Hisar district. In her three years with the organization, she both laid the groundwork and built upon it a healthy system focused on educative, co-curricular, and extra-curricular activities. Her work was recognized with awards and recognition from the HRD Ministry, as well as frequent facilitations by local TV, radio, and newspaper entities. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Before taking up administration as her primary focus, Shalini was an English teacher at various prestigious organizations in Rajasthan and Haryana. She began her career at B. R. Birla Public School, Jodhpur, in 1999 teaching junior classes foundations of the English language. After spending 4 years with young children, she realized that she can make a bigger impact to the general level of education and student growth by working with adolescents, teens, and pre-teens. She began teaching at a senior secondary level in Sohan Lal Manihar School, Jodhpur, in 2003. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Her growing reputation meant that she was a primary candidate to bolster the English department at Delhi Public School, Jodhpur, in 2004 as the school was just finding its feet and establishing itself as a strong brand in the unconquered market of central Rajasthan. She stayed there for about 8 years, helping DPS first find its feet and later become the </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">leading institution in the area. As a pioneer of new-age technologies, she was appointed as the head of the school’s digital presence and website management. Her organizational and disciplinary skills led her to become the school’s face for inter-school operations, including sports meets, Olympiads, as well as literary conventions and competitions. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In 2011, she moved back to her home state of Haryana, when she agreed to join O. P. Jindal Modern School, Hisar. She brought her experience and expertise from her previous work and set out to improving the educational foundations of the school. As the coordinator for the English department at the school, her responsibilities were not only literary but structural. She created and lead the debating society at the school, in addition to spearheading the supervision committees for operational and ceremonial aspects of the student body, including investiture ceremonies, daily assemblies, and annual functions. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In conclusion, while Shalini has held varied titles in varied geographies, her core mission has remained the same for the past 20 years – using education as a tool to improve the society from the ground up. As a student of English as well as Psychology, she understands that the best way to make systemic and lasting improvement is to teach the upcoming generation the best of what we know. That insight coupled with her incessant drive means that she has been delivering results in her field endlessly, and will continue to do so. Fiat lux. </span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Guidance and Counselling</title>
        <author>
            <name>Shalini Chaudhary</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://soigne68.github.io/guidance-and-counselling.html"/>
        <id>https://soigne68.github.io/guidance-and-counselling.html</id>

        <updated>2022-01-23T23:30:25+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Guidance and Counselling are very important tools to educate children and the schools have a tremendous responsibility of effectively bringing out the best in them. The need of guidance and counselling can be stated in simple terms to assist and help individuals adjust to their&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><span class="ILfuVd"><span class="hgKElc">Guidance and Counselling are very important tools to educate children and the schools have a tremendous responsibility of effectively bringing out the best in them. <span dir="ltr" role="presentation">The need of guidance and counselling </span><span dir="ltr" role="presentation">can be stated in simple terms to assist and help individuals adjust to their personal, </span><span dir="ltr" role="presentation">emotional, educational and occupational environment. Many a time, working parents are not able to give quality time to their children or pin point the root cause of their alienated behaviour. The role of guidance counsellors comes to the forefront in these situations. Guidance counsellors helps them to react to situations by developing new strategies and dealing with them in an efficacious manner. Counsellors render a professional service to the individuals who are facing some problem and needs help to overcome it. Guidance and counselling is oriented to help students understand themselves, become self-sufficient in making realistic and positive selections and grow in human relationships and concerns. Counselling sessions are a gradual process to mould and redirect children towards a brighter career. It also gives wings to the dreams of children through different vocational and career oriented guidance.</span></span></span></p>
<p>In the one-to-one counselling sessions, it's imperative that the child should feel safe and secure in the company of the counsellor and know that he/she is not being judged. The counsellor can ask questions but should not probe the child's privacy to an unacceptable level. Children are more comfortable in sharing their ideas with someone who is more objective  and not biased about them.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Responsibilities of a counsellor</span>-</p>
<ul>
<li>Facilitating the students in becoming more productive and dynamic members of the society</li>
<li>Providing emotional security and comfort</li>
<li>Helping in promoting insight</li>
<li>Leading to self awareness</li>
<li>Encouraging confidence</li>
<li>Ensuring confidentiality</li>
<li>Developing a positive self image</li>
<li>Building rapport</li>
</ul>
<p>A counsellor must show responsible and trustworthy behaviour with a positive and constructive problem solving approach. Their tone of voice should express interest and concern. Their body language, facial expressions, gestures and comments should be very structured and thoughtful. At no given point, should the child feel that they are being judged.</p>
<p>As far as guidance is concerned, young minds need it to polish their personality. Guidance sessions advise the children about selection of courses and different career opportunities, enabling them to make proper and informed choices for their future. It's important to prepare children for life after school and what to expect in the different fields they might opt for. Professional guidance helps the students to achieve their goals in the best possible manner. It not only helps them to take decisions pertaining to their career, but it also makes them confident and mentally prepares them for the challenges. They acquire knowledge, attitude and inter-personal skills to set their own goals and take their own decisions to achieve those goals. Along with their academic and career development, their social and personal development is also taken care of. Guidance and counselling makes students better informed individuals.</p>
<p>All over the world children are under extreme stress and anxiety due to performance issues. In India, the education system focusses more on quantitative learning with long school hours, heavy school bags and rote learning which leads to lesser creativity and innovation in the teaching and learning process. Now-a-days some educational institutions have come up with more technology based teaching, but there is a long way to go. Let us join hands to bring more quality to the education system with structured guidance and counselling to all the three stake holders of the education system, i.e. students, parents and teachers.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Year 2021</title>
        <author>
            <name>Shalini Chaudhary</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://soigne68.github.io/year-2021.html"/>
        <id>https://soigne68.github.io/year-2021.html</id>

        <updated>2021-12-31T21:23:03+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                     "Celebrate endings-for they precede new beginnings." Once again the time has come, when we sit back and introspect the year that is just slipping away from the calender. How fascinating is it that time passes by at its normal pace every single day and&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>                    <strong><em>"Celebrate endings-for they precede new beginnings."</em></strong></p>
<p>Once again the time has come, when we sit back and introspect the year that is just slipping away from the calender. How fascinating is it that time passes by at its normal pace every single day and once we reach to the end of the year, everyone comments,"Kaise beet gaya ek saal, pata hi nahin chala!"</p>
<p>The year 2021 came with its own challenges and promises. I sincerely thank God for blessing me and my loved ones with health and happiness and pray for this Heavenly benediction to continue in the years to come. I personally found a different meaning to my life this year. It was a rigmarole of events constantly happening almost the same way. In the past few years, my shift from a teacher to an administrator was exceptionally interesting. It was a great learning experience during all those years (on both sides of the table :)). But then, a desire to be my own master was always haunting me. Finally, the month of June 2021 witnessed the change and instead of being an employee, I became an employer. There was constant support from my family and friends and I sincerely thank them for their unflinching faith and confidence in me. It has given me a new level of understanding about my own capabilities.</p>
<p>As a country also, we have seen innumerable changes and events. There was a time when some people were battling for oxygen and some were hoarding it for emergent times. There were Samaritans who didn't let the faith in humanity die and worked tirelessly to bring hope and cheer in those desperate times. A big salute to all those people! Then we had the best Olympics tally of medals this year with a Gold Medal. India secured 47th position from the 65th position. Indeed a proud moment for all Indians! There were amazing contributions in the field of science and technology also with the unmanned space mission to the moon and launching of a nuclear submarine. The list is endless when we look towards the positive side and so is the list on the other side too. What matters is our perception! The year has given us a new insight with life changing experiences and we must step into 2022 with a new determination and hope. Many people change with the time and then there are a few who change the time. May we be the harbingers of change and bring glory to our being!</p>
<p>Let's move into 2022 with a resolution. A resolution to be more purposeful, humanitarian and loving. Work is important but it's also imperative to maintain our health. Keep scheduled working hours, visit your family, friends and invest in relations. Appreciate and enjoy the beauty of nature. We get this life once. Make the most of it.</p>
<p>Goodbye 2021! Welcome 2022....</p>
<p>Wish you all a very happy and prosperous new year! May it be filled with new adventures, happy times and good fortunes!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Show gratitude in all your actions!</title>
        <author>
            <name>Shalini Chaudhary</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://soigne68.github.io/show-gratitude-in-all-your-actions.html"/>
        <id>https://soigne68.github.io/show-gratitude-in-all-your-actions.html</id>

        <updated>2021-10-07T18:09:06+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    "Acknowledging the good that you already have in your life is the foundation for all abundance." I strongly believe in this quote because being thankful for what we have paves the way for more to come. Practicing this turns the excruciating pain of difficult times&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><em><strong>"Acknowledging the good that you already have in your life is the foundation for all abundance."</strong></em></p>
<p>I strongly believe in this quote because being thankful for what we have paves the way for more to come. Practicing this turns the excruciating pain of difficult times into tolerable ones. We shouldn't be deterred by the unfavourable events taking place in our lives, as these events only bring out our real resilient self into full projection. Even if the things are going wrong, set your vibrations into the tuning mode of your choice and see the difference. I know for a fact that it's easy said being done. But believe me, once you practice this art, you will find a different meaning to your life. </p>
<p>Let me give you a quick example. Around a decade ago, there came a night that seemed to loom larger then my existence. I was left devastated, broken and shattered by circumstances. I had my children with me and that was the only sunshine in the otherwise pitch dark scenario. I thanked God for what I had and tried to move on. I won't lie. I did cry in the initial phase but time is a great healer. It taught me that the  universe aligns us with people, things and situations. If there is something that is not required in our life, universe conspires to throw it out of the system. It may take time but it will definitely work for our betterment. Today, when I look back, I thank God for chartering this path for me. I bow my head in complete reverence to Him for blessing me with two mature individuals as my children. What troubled me didn't vanish suddenly, but I moved out of my tunnel vision of looking at things and tried to broaden my horizon into the periphery of my life where amazing things were happening in different manners.  We only need to arrange or orchestrate the things for desired results. There comes a time when you realise that everything that you've gone through was actually a blessing in disguise.</p>
<p>When we are building ourselves for a better tomorrow, there shouldn't be any time to dwell on the small little things actually petty things of yesterday. Make gratitude a fundamental feature of your existence. Right in the morning when you open your eyes, thank God for blessing you with a new day and promise yourself to do the best you can to make the day a remarkable one. When you sleep at night thank all those people in your heart, who helped you to achieve your goals during the day. It's a very healing exercise. If you can thank people in person, don't lose the chance. You never know you may not get the opportunity again. There goes a story about a man whose life was saved only because he had the habit of thanking the security guard before leaving for the day. One day he was locked in his office and couldn't reach anyone for help. The security guard raised an alarm about it because he hadn't seen him going and saved his life. </p>
<p>Every person is struggling his or her own battle. We should try to be kind and generous in all our ways and means. As we navigate the highs and lows in life, the love and compassion we share with others gives the direction and brightness to life. Let this journey be a journey of healing to make this world a better place to live. I thank you all for being there with me.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Change is inevitable</title>
        <author>
            <name>Shalini Chaudhary</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://soigne68.github.io/change-is-inevitable.html"/>
        <id>https://soigne68.github.io/change-is-inevitable.html</id>

        <updated>2021-07-04T21:45:03+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    There are times when we don't want to risk change in our otherwise comfortable lifestyles. We strive hard to remain in our comfort zone and resist all changes. As a result, our growth doesn't reach to its full bloom. We condition ourselves to a stagnant&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>There are times when we don't want to risk change in our otherwise comfortable lifestyles. We strive hard to remain in our comfort zone and resist all changes. As a result, our growth doesn't reach to its full bloom. We condition ourselves to a stagnant life  and as a consequence live a life like the Dead Sea. The Sea of Galilee also receives the water from the same source (Jordan river), but is resplendent with flourishing flora and fauna, only because it allows the water to come and go. On the other hand the Dead Sea retains the water and ultimately annihilates all chances of life. The most important feature that we need to understand is that change brings a new sunshine everywhere. Nature is the best example here.</p>
<p>These changes, whether internal/external teach us something new. Most of the times external changes propel us to make a shift in the internal programming, which inturn brings a change in our behaviour, our thinking and reacting to any situation. For personal growth, it's important to bring voluntary changes in our lives, by embracing new challenges with resilience and power. To become a better version of ourselves, we must work internally like the Chinese Bamboo (which takes years to show the first sign of life, but when it does, it dazzles the whole world with its phenomenal growth).</p>
<p>As a human being, we get anxious with change. And it's quite natural too, because we have been wired like this from the starting. I am not suggesting that we should change everything, but we must give sometime to ourselves and ask-Where do I want to be five/ten years down the line? If the answer is different from your your current lifestyle then gear up to change because merely wishing won't manifest the desire into reality. Set up a long term goal and break it into small achievable goals and then work with patience and persistence to achieve them with panache. </p>
<p>Set your principles in tune with your goals to guide you better. You don't know how something will turn out when you act, but you do know whether this action is in line with your principles or not. Show strength in dealing with whatever outcome and you will find yourself in a better position. For example, some of my guiding principles are to become an entrepreneur, travel worldwide, to read and write extensively, build trust and create a better society. To achieve these, I had to make some changes in my thought process. Leaving a regular job with a regular paycheck is risky but liberating and profound. I have committed to myself to achieve all these goals in this lifetime only.</p>
<p>Being true and honest, to one's own self is very important to reach the desired position. At times, we don't know the nuances of many things. Be a learner there, instead of diving headfirst in the unknown waters. Update your skills, have faith and be the CHANGE. </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Life is a canvas!</title>
        <author>
            <name>Shalini Chaudhary</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://soigne68.github.io/life-is-a-canvas.html"/>
        <id>https://soigne68.github.io/life-is-a-canvas.html</id>

        <updated>2021-07-04T21:38:07+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    This Holi, let's all resolve to fill our life with myriad colours. It's in our hands that we paint the canvas of our lives with colours of positivity or the other way round. Colours radiate with dazzling shine when they emanate from the heart. Nature&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>This Holi, let's all resolve to fill our life with myriad colours. It's in our hands that we paint the canvas of our lives with colours of positivity or the other way round. Colours radiate with dazzling shine when they emanate from the heart. Nature teaches us the beauty of each colour. The rising sun with its orange colour gives warmth and then it's bright yellow colour promises happiness, hope and cheer. It brightens up each and every corner of the earth. The vast sky with it's blue colour gives us peace and calmness. It sends a message that there is no end to posibilities. We only have to set our eyes on our goal and work persistently. Red colour radiates love in all it's forms. The beautiful red rose mesmerises us with it's beauty and fragrance and even when you pluck it, it won't lose it's beauty. Purple colour motivates us to be kind and compassionate and so on...</p>
<p>The best part is that we have all this in our lives without any prejudice. I feel, we can use this abundance not only to beautify our own life but also to give meaning to our existence. This precious lifetime has more significance, if we impact other lives. Knowingly or unknowingly, we leave a mark on others. Let that be a remarkable one. At times, a small gesture of giving a smile to somebody changes the life course of that person. May be that person required just a reassuring smile to move on. Be that angel in the lives of others. You can make the difference. Life may not be very happening all the time, but remaining grumpy won't solve the problem. You have to move on and see the bright side. There are positives in negatives too. I remember a story that I had read some time back, which talks about a mother and her daughter. The mother was bogged down by the amount of work that she had to do and the daughter was doing her homework of writing a paragraph on "Negative Thanks Giving". The girl was writing about the things, which didn't please her initially but had a rewarding ending. Like the bad medicine which tasted bitter but cured her from the ailment or the final exams which meant holidays are round the corner. The lady could understand that, this amount of work means she has a shelter to live in and people in her life to look after and her whole mind set was changed. We should look at the better part of life and make every day a great day. Why not to make this life a life of gratitude? Because, it will unlock the magnificence of life.   </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Adventure is just a moment away!</title>
        <author>
            <name>Shalini Chaudhary</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://soigne68.github.io/adventure-is-just-a-moment-away-3.html"/>
        <id>https://soigne68.github.io/adventure-is-just-a-moment-away-3.html</id>

        <updated>2021-07-04T21:48:57+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    It took me a little longer to get back to my routine of writing posts, as promised, but I was on a journey...an adventurous journey with Bilbo Baggins. It has reiterated my conviction that, "The world is not in your books and maps. It's out&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>It took me a little longer to get back to my routine of writing posts, as promised, but I was on a journey...an adventurous journey with Bilbo Baggins. It has reiterated my conviction that, "The world is not in your books and maps. It's out there". We need to have that spirit of moving out from our comfort zone and explore the unknown.</p>
<p>This journey started with my picking the book "The Hobbit" by J.R.R. Tolkiens. It's a fantasy novel for children and when I laid my hands on it, I was wondering about the experience. I was not sure about it's completion. It all started with a doubt and a light hearted desire to read a novel for children, which had won acclaim all over the world. It was indeed an unforgettable journey. The main character- Bilbo Baggins, is presented as the most complacent creature, living a pretty average life in his hole. But once he was challenged for an adventure and the way he fought with Smaug (dragon) single handedly to reclaim the lost treasure, it simply projects him as the real hero. We can't say that he reclaimed his lost power, because he got the power which he didn't know he had. He was in complete amazement with himself because slaying the huge spider or fighting with the slimy Gollum without the help of Gandalf (wizard) or dwarves was a nightmare for him. He realized that - Happiness lies in knowing our worth. The fiercer and bolder Hobbit found a new meaning to life.</p>
<p>It cemented my belief that the ability to take action in the face of fear is the most crucial thing. Rest happens automatically. Once you win the battle with your mind then no force can stop you to scale greater heights. Most of the times we are slaves to our own inhibitions and don't allow ourselves to step out and take the challenge. What is most important in life is the faith in our abilities. We live in a society where most of the times,  our roles are pre-defined and we also believe in our limited capacity. We just have to break free the shackles and build a new pesona. President Roosevelt's words are very apt to quote here," The only thing we have to fear is...fear itself - nameless, unreasoning, unjustified terror which paralyzes needed efforts to convert retreat into advance".</p>
<p>There is one more instance where Tolkien has truly presented a great idea. It was when Gandalf along with Thorin and company (dwarves) persuaded Baggins for the adventure.</p>
<p>Baggins asked,"<em><strong>You can promise that I'll come back?</strong></em>"</p>
<p>And Gandalf answered, <em><strong>"No. And if you do, you'll not be the same."</strong></em></p>
<p>What a beautiful interpretation! It actually stirs a positive thought process. And yes, it proved right, because Baggins was a changed creature after the sinister fight. He had shown extreme mental fortitude when he gave the Arkenstone (Stone which gives you the infinite powers) to the army of men and elves instead of his comrades, so that the damaging war and bloodshed can be avoided. Later on risking his own safety, he returned to his people with a deep loyalty. His transformation from a shy and timid creature to a true hero is a classic example of fighting your own battles. </p>
<p>I recommend this book to those who can appreciate the subtleness of ideas. The dialogues are comical and hilarious at times, targetting the readers for whom it was originally written, but they do add to the overall beauty of the book.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>All The Light We Cannot See</title>
        <author>
            <name>Shalini Chaudhary</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://soigne68.github.io/all-the-light-we-cannot-see.html"/>
        <id>https://soigne68.github.io/all-the-light-we-cannot-see.html</id>

        <updated>2021-10-07T18:11:50+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    There comes a time in life when we are blinded by the outer light and completely merge with the system of extravaganza. We start believing that to be the truth of life and expect no escape. We don't even feel that something is missing and&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>There comes a time in life when we are blinded by the outer light and completely merge with the system of extravaganza. We start believing that to be the truth of life and expect no escape. We don't even feel that something is missing and some concrete action is required to bring in the much needed change. Constant pressure of work, life, relationships, society and what not... is being harped upon in a continuous process. And we don't even realize the light within, which has the ultimate power to transmute the mundane into magical.</p>
<p>This was the scenario of my life also around four months back. When I was a self proclaimed victim of extreme work and pressure. But, since the day I have actively started reading books...once again...I find a tremendous change in the thought process. There seems to be a complete overhaul of the system. And, mind you, it feels good. The words of Francis Bacon resound in my mind and I quote,'Reading maketh a full man; conference a ready man; and writing an exact man". This world of books has given a new perspective to life. Recently, I have read the book, All the light We Cannot See, by Anthony Doerr and it has completely changed my idea about blind people. Marie Laure, the main character of the story is blind, but the way she persevers and sustains in life is mind boggling. Her blindness never impedes her way to achieve excellence. The words, <em>Open your eyes and see what you can with them before they close forever,</em> have left an everlastng impression on me. It's true that it doesn't matter how many resources we have unless and until we know how to use them. Time is a very crucial thing and it goes without saying that once you lose hold of it, it almost gets impossible to catch the strings. Another character of the story, Werner, is an exceptionally intelligent boy with mechanical, technical and scientific knowledge. He was an orphan but his fascination to see the invisible waves took him to places. There is such a realistic presentation of the brutality of Nazi's and the traumatic experience of fleeing to other countries for peace, that at times it leaves you in pieces. </p>
<p>I could feel the light within each word and each expression of the book. Anthony Doerr has certainly found a place in  the list of my favourite writers. While reading the book, there were times, when I caught myself just staring at the words and drowning in the memories of my visit to Auschwitz (Krakow, Poland), where I could see the gas chambers and the depth of brutality by Hitler Army. </p>
<p>Now, that I am reading a book/week, I will put my reviews here, so that my readers may also get interested to delve deeper into the world of books.</p>
<p>It's a beautiful world. Let's weave each day with good ideas, plan each move for betterment and see the light within!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Setting Priorities</title>
        <author>
            <name>Shalini Chaudhary</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://soigne68.github.io/setting-priorities.html"/>
        <id>https://soigne68.github.io/setting-priorities.html</id>

        <updated>2020-08-22T20:58:41+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    We all wish to succeed and leave a mark in the pages of history, but don't plan a winning strategy for the same. As we move on in life, we come across varied experiences and find that one of the biggest challenges in life is&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>We all wish to succeed and leave a mark in the pages of history, but don't plan a winning strategy for the same. As we move on in life, we come across varied experiences and find that one of the biggest challenges in life is to become comfortable in uncomfortable situations. You step into your greatness only when you decide to step out of your comfort zone. Going by the flow and letting things happen to you will result in anaverage life. It's for us to decide what kind of life we envisage for ourselves.</p>
<p>I feel, that if our life goal is clear, then we won't have any regrets on the day of judgement. We must understand what we actually require and what requires to be left behind. As soon as we have the clarity of purpose, life will get its meaning. Life has precisely the meaning that we give to it.</p>
<p>Our priority in life should be to ensure our happiness in our being. Never feel depressed about what people say about you. If you are true to yourself, believe in your actions and can feel proud by the end of the day, then it doesn't matter what people say about you. Take the charge of your life and be successful.</p>
<p> Don't sit on the comforting couch basking in the glory of your achievements. Each day is a challenge and we must prove our mettle through perseverance. If one fine day, we feel that life is all settled and we need not work hard to improve then it's nothing less then the murder of our better version. We fear changes because they shake our comfort but actually these changes are instrumental in our growth. These days of Covid-19 have taught this to us in the most effective manner. We had never thought of this system of online education and initially there were lot of hiccups and bumpy roads. But now everything has come to a new normal. Old ways don't open new doors. We should be confident to take the risk or lose the chance. </p>
<p>At times, we learn this lesson the hard way. It's when we lose the opportunity that we grumble over its loss. Take the life by its reins. You are the master of your fate, and the captain of your soul.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
