<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Shalini Chaudhary</title>
    <link href="https://soigne68.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://soigne68.github.io" />
    <updated>2022-10-14T21:57:41+05:30</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Shalini Chaudhary</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://soigne68.github.io</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Beauty personified!</title>
        <author>
            <name>Shalini Chaudhary</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://soigne68.github.io/beauty-personified.html"/>
        <id>https://soigne68.github.io/beauty-personified.html</id>

        <updated>2022-10-14T21:57:41+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    It's time to share my experience of visiting Taj mahal and nearby areas (something that I had promised two posts back:) ). That trip was like a magical experience. Since my childhood, I had a desire to visit Taj Mahal (among other places). One fine&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>It's time to share my experience of visiting Taj mahal and nearby areas (something that I had promised two posts back:) ).  That trip was like a magical experience. Since my childhood, I had a desire to visit Taj Mahal (among other places). One fine day my son announced that we are going to Agra. To be honest, my first expression was of disbelief as we had a plan to go towards the eastern side covering Amritsar, Fazilka and Kartarpur. Going to Agra was like taking a detour but still we did it. Visiting Agra was like a dream come true situation. It was truly an intoxicating moment, when I saw the grand monument of love in all its glory in the morning hours of 28th June.  </p>
<p>I was speechless and completely blown by its beauty. Undoubtedly, it's the best example of Mughal architecture. The milky white structure was loud in its silence. The magnificent Yamuna river  in the back side added to its charm. It was disturbing to see that the walls were distorted due to unnecessary scribbling by people but then I believe if you can't change something, live with it. I loved each moment that was spent there and while I am writing about it (after around three months), it feels like I am visiting the place again. I have brought that charm with me and live it each day. Taj Mahal is not a place, it's an emotion and anyone who has visited it once with a purity of heart and a sincere desire to be a part of that history can never escape from the indulgence. It's a commitment. It clearly exhibits that love can move mountains. </p>
<p>We had also visited Akbar's tomb and Fatehpur Sikri. Spread in around 119 acres, the tomb leaves you spell bound with its beauty and architecture. I was completely immersed and mesmerised by the sheer elegance of the place. Visiting his grave in the basement was nothing short of a revealation. One has to pass through a small tunnel kind of structure to reach the grave. The walls are painted in different colours and the whole ambience is breathtaking. The quietness of the place quietens everything and leaves you thinking about the mortality of life. I also came to know that Akbar had designed the architecture of his tomb and the work started in his lifetime. Quite impressive! ...His interest of amalgamating various religions and bringing out the best is aptly portrayed there. We also went to the Kaanch mahal and Jodha Bai's palace. The intricate design and simplicity of the place was par excellence.</p>
<p>Overall, visiting Agra was a great experience and driving on the Yamuna expressway was an added charm.</p>
<p> </p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/20/551AC28B-FD46-4B09-B58A-54D5C3686FB6.JPEG" sizes="(min-width: 61.3125em) 50vw, 100vw" srcset="https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/20/responsive/551AC28B-FD46-4B09-B58A-54D5C3686FB6-xs.JPEG 300w ,https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/20/responsive/551AC28B-FD46-4B09-B58A-54D5C3686FB6-sm.JPEG 480w ,https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/20/responsive/551AC28B-FD46-4B09-B58A-54D5C3686FB6-md.JPEG 768w"  alt="" width="3241" height="1956"></figure>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/20/985CE79E-64CC-4BB2-B979-D520FA2AA33C.JPEG" sizes="(min-width: 61.3125em) 50vw, 100vw" srcset="https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/20/responsive/985CE79E-64CC-4BB2-B979-D520FA2AA33C-xs.JPEG 300w ,https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/20/responsive/985CE79E-64CC-4BB2-B979-D520FA2AA33C-sm.JPEG 480w ,https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/20/responsive/985CE79E-64CC-4BB2-B979-D520FA2AA33C-md.JPEG 768w"  alt="" width="3346" height="2194"></figure>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/20/B0BF7AE6-0183-40EE-987C-FD78C0BAA685.JPEG" sizes="(min-width: 61.3125em) 50vw, 100vw" srcset="https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/20/responsive/B0BF7AE6-0183-40EE-987C-FD78C0BAA685-xs.JPEG 300w ,https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/20/responsive/B0BF7AE6-0183-40EE-987C-FD78C0BAA685-sm.JPEG 480w ,https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/20/responsive/B0BF7AE6-0183-40EE-987C-FD78C0BAA685-md.JPEG 768w"  alt="" width="3387" height="2241"></figure>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/20/E08DD7CD-0F24-491E-B2E3-7114352E8A63.JPEG" sizes="(min-width: 61.3125em) 50vw, 100vw" srcset="https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/20/responsive/E08DD7CD-0F24-491E-B2E3-7114352E8A63-xs.JPEG 300w ,https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/20/responsive/E08DD7CD-0F24-491E-B2E3-7114352E8A63-sm.JPEG 480w ,https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/20/responsive/E08DD7CD-0F24-491E-B2E3-7114352E8A63-md.JPEG 768w"  alt="" width="3466" height="1475"></figure>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>वो फ़्रेम की कहानी !</title>
        <author>
            <name>Shalini Chaudhary</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://soigne68.github.io/vo-phrem-kii-khaanii.html"/>
        <id>https://soigne68.github.io/vo-phrem-kii-khaanii.html</id>

        <updated>2022-09-13T22:53:27+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    ख़ाली दीवार पर टंगा वो फ़्रेम, और फ़्रेम में टंगा वो जीवन, जो ताउम्र लड़ता रहा अपनों के लिए नहीं बता पाता अपनी दुशवारियाँ I नहीं बता पाता उस बेरंग जीवन की कहानी, जो भरने चला था रंग चहुँ ओर I चाहत थी उसकी पाई&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><em>ख़ाली  दीवार पर </em></p>
<p><em>टंगा वो फ़्रेम,</em></p>
<p>और<em> फ़्रेम में टंगा वो जीवन,</em></p>
<p><em>जो ताउम्र लड़ता रहा अपनों के लिए </em></p>
<p><em>नहीं बता पाता अपनी दुशवारियाँ I </em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>नहीं बता पाता उस बेरंग जीवन की कहानी,</em></p>
<p><em>जो भरने चला था रंग चहुँ ओर I </em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>चाहत थी उसकी पाई -पाई जोड़ कर </em></p>
<p><em>बना ले अपने अपनों के लिए महल </em></p>
<p><em>छोड़ जाए एक विरासत </em></p>
<p><em>अपनी विरासत के नाम I </em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>पर किसे मालूम था,</em></p>
<p><em>जब लेगा वो अंतिम साँस,</em></p>
<p><em>उसके अपने ही बदलने लगेंगे कांधा,</em></p>
<p><em>पहुँचाने को उसको उसकी मंज़िल I </em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>उसका यह सूनापन देता है संदेश,</em></p>
<p><em>जी लो यह जीवन अपनी ख़ातिर,</em></p>
<p><em>क्योंकि कोई ना है तुम्हारी ख़ातिर I </em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>तुम तुम हो, जब तक है साँस,</em></p>
<p><em>फिर तो हो मांस का एक गट्ठर,</em></p>
<p><em>जिसे मिला देना है बिछड़ी माटी से </em></p>
<p><em>कर हवाले शोलों  के I </em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>और फिर शुरू होना है </em></p>
<p><em>एक और सफ़र,</em></p>
<p><em>हर साल की बरसी पर </em></p>
<p><em>जब तुम बरबस ही खिंचे चले आओगे ,</em></p>
<p><em>अपने अपनों के पास I </em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>महसूस करोगे वो धड़कन,</em></p>
<p><em>मुस्कुराओगे उस आयोजन पर,</em></p>
<p><em>और फिर से चले जाओगे </em></p>
<p><em>उसी फ़्रेम की दुनिया में I </em></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>हाँ, मैं बदल गयी हूँ !</title>
        <author>
            <name>Shalini Chaudhary</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://soigne68.github.io/haan-main-bdl-gyii-huun.html"/>
        <id>https://soigne68.github.io/haan-main-bdl-gyii-huun.html</id>

        <updated>2022-09-13T22:55:19+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    अब नहीं तकती राह मैं हर हाँ की, नहीं करती इंतज़ार सहमति का, मुझे फ़ख़्र है अपने आप पर ग़ुरूर है अपने ज़मीर पर, हाँ, मैं बदल गयी हूँ I नहीं है चाह मुझे हमदर्दी की, ना इच्छा है सहानुभूति की, मैं हूँ अपने आप&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>अब नहीं तकती राह मैं हर हाँ की,</p>
<p>नहीं करती इंतज़ार सहमति का,</p>
<p>मुझे फ़ख़्र है अपने आप पर </p>
<p>ग़ुरूर है अपने ज़मीर पर,</p>
<p>हाँ, मैं बदल गयी हूँ I </p>
<p> </p>
<p>नहीं है चाह मुझे हमदर्दी की,</p>
<p>ना इच्छा है सहानुभूति की,</p>
<p>मैं हूँ अपने आप में मशगूल </p>
<p>बेक़रार हूँ करने को एक नया शोर </p>
<p>हाँ, मैं बदल गयी हूँ I </p>
<p> </p>
<p>शोर जो सुनाई दे बहरे को,</p>
<p>दिखाई दे जो एक अंधे को,</p>
<p>ठहरा दे  साँसे जो इस ज़माने की </p>
<p>तोड़ दे हर बंदिश पैमाने की </p>
<p>हाँ, मैं बदल गयी हूँ I  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>To teach is to learn!</title>
        <author>
            <name>Shalini Chaudhary</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://soigne68.github.io/to-teach-is-to-learn.html"/>
        <id>https://soigne68.github.io/to-teach-is-to-learn.html</id>

        <updated>2022-09-06T21:29:42+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    This Teachers’ Day I want to thank all those who have taught me- formally or informally, directly or indirectly, willingly or unwillingly. Whatever I have achieved till date is all because of their presence in my life. I strongly believe that learning never stops and&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>This Teachers’ Day I want to thank all those who have taught me- formally or informally, directly or indirectly, willingly or unwillingly. Whatever I have achieved till date  is all because of their presence in my life. I strongly believe that learning never stops and even after more than five decades of my life I am a curious learner. I have formally left the job in education sector and started my career as an entrepreneur. I am learning the business nuances and thank my children for guiding me at each step, whether it's product management or marketing strategy.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>My blessings to all my students, who have also helped me in shaping my personality. The students for whom I was a Principal, an English teacher, a Class teacher or a Mentor. It's an amazing feeling to walk down the memory lane and recall the innocent faces of all the children with whom I started my career in 1994. Since then, there is no looking back and I have tutored hundreds and thousands of students in different capacities. Nurturing their high level of energy with utmost passion and dedication and helping them channelize it in a productive manner has always been a challenging (seriously…) and rewarding task. This day gets more significant because many of my old students who are doing great in their lives as engineers, doctors, administrators, defence personnel, businessman or …(list is too long😋) take out time from their schedule and thank me for helping them shape their lives in a better manner. Since morning, I am getting messages from my students and teachers expressing their love and affection. I am truly humbled and overwhelmed. It gives even more sense of responsibility to keep doing my best and raise the bar of excellence. </p>
<p> </p>
<p> I wish to suggest the teaching fraternity that you have a very significant role to play in the lives of children. Teaching is not a profession. It’s a Bhakti (Meditation). You are shaping the future of the world. Try to be a role model for them. They look at you with utmost faith which even surpasses the parents’ impact. Always practice before you preach. Promote good values, punctiliousness and love for discipline. You have a gift of influencing lives both inside and outside of the classroom. Never give up on your students. This is one such profession, which is a win-win situation for both the stakeholders- teachers and students. Students get the knowledge from their teachers and teachers also learn many things while teaching. </p>
<p>Happy teaching! May we all help each other to become a better version of ourselves!</p>
<p>Wishing you all health, happiness and success!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Down the Memory Lane</title>
        <author>
            <name>Shalini Chaudhary</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://soigne68.github.io/down-the-memory-lane.html"/>
        <id>https://soigne68.github.io/down-the-memory-lane.html</id>

        <updated>2022-08-16T21:42:26+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/16/IMG_3771.png" alt="" />
                    Taj mahal- Check Akbar’s Tomb- Check Fatehpur Sikri- Check Darbar Sahib, Kartarpur, Pakistan- Check Nishan Sahib Market- Check Golden Temple- Check Wagah Border- Check Sikh Museum – Check Jallianwala Bagh- Check Partition Museum- Check Hussainiwala Border- Check National Martyrs Memorial, Hussainiwala- Check War Memorial- Check&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/16/IMG_3771.png" alt="" />
                <p>Taj mahal- Check</p>
<p>Akbar’s Tomb- Check</p>
<p>Fatehpur Sikri- Check</p>
<p>Darbar Sahib, Kartarpur, Pakistan- Check</p>
<p>Nishan Sahib Market- Check</p>
<p>Golden Temple- Check</p>
<p>Wagah Border- Check</p>
<p>Sikh Museum – Check</p>
<p>Jallianwala Bagh- Check</p>
<p>Partition Museum- Check</p>
<p>Hussainiwala Border- Check</p>
<p>National Martyrs Memorial, Hussainiwala- Check</p>
<p>War Memorial- Check</p>
<p>Fazilka Border- Check</p>
<p>These 14 places were covered in 7 days, and it was indeed the most memorable summer of 2022. We could cover 4 borders (Kartarpur, Wagah, Hussainiwala and Fazilka) with Pakistan in 4 days. Incredible indeed! </p>
<p>Today when I am writing this blog, the memories of visiting the partition museum in Amritsar come alive in my heart. We bask in the glory of independence, but we should never forget the sacrifices of those unsung heroes who had to suffer inconsolably. I had heard the real-life accounts of people who shared that their destinies were changed overnight due to a line drawn by Cyril Radcliffe. The drawing of the boundary proved to be extremely controversial for thousands and thousands of families as they found themselves uprooted from a land which they had inhabited for generations. It was very painful to watch and hear those accounts. But I appreciate the fact that the museum has kept the essence alive and only an insensitive soul can fail to feel the pain.</p>
<p>I had heard a lot about Wagah border and went their with a lot of enthusiasm. It was a good experience but when I visited Hussainiwala border, it superseded all rankings. I could feel the pulse of patriotism in each and every person there. There was amazing coordination and camaraderie in the soldiers from both the countries. The ceremonial gestures of showing their valour and power were captivating. The soldiers exchanged their positions during the ‘Retreat Ceremony’, which means Indian soldier went to Pakistan's side and Pakistani soldier came to India's side. This was a unique moment as the National flags of both the countries were lowered before the dusk. Fazilka border ceremony was also energising. The energy and ferocity of soldiers in all the border ceremonies was contagious. People were taking selfies with soldiers, regarding them as heroes and feeling proud to be there. No doubt, our real heroes are the soldiers of the country. I salute them and pay my respect for all the sacrifices they make for us. </p>
<p>I must talk about Kartarpur corridor separately, because that was the highlight of the visit.</p>
<figure class="post__image align-center"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/16/236BAE81-8558-4B3F-8462-E5D7886BD40A.png" sizes="(min-width: 61.3125em) 50vw, 100vw" srcset="https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/16/responsive/236BAE81-8558-4B3F-8462-E5D7886BD40A-xs.png 300w ,https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/16/responsive/236BAE81-8558-4B3F-8462-E5D7886BD40A-sm.png 480w ,https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/16/responsive/236BAE81-8558-4B3F-8462-E5D7886BD40A-md.png 768w"  alt="" width="3413" height="1276"></figure>
<p>We had applied for the visit very well in advance and got police verification done. I was personally very excited for this as we were going to Pakistan- our own land before partition. Once we reached the corridor, we passed through all custom formalities and entered Pakistan. The people were very hospitable and the shrine was mesmerising. This is the final resting place of Guru Nanak Dev Ji. It is said that Guru Nanak ji did farming in this area till the time of his eternal sleep. His three principles of <span style="color: #000000;"><em><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kirat_Karo" style="color: #000000;">Kirat Karo</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Naam_Japo" style="color: #000000;">Naam Japo</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vand_Chhako" style="color: #000000;">Wand Chako</a>,</em></span>( work hard for a livelihood, keep remembering the God and share your blessings with the world) are the real teachings. The place is huge and very well maintained. I feel blessed to get an opportunity to go there and would love to visit again. The peace and tranquillity of the place was matchless. The next best part was the Nishan Sahib market. I got many souvenirs from there and the best one is this.</p>
<figure class="post__image align-center"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/16/IMG_4147.png" sizes="(min-width: 61.3125em) 50vw, 100vw" srcset="https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/16/responsive/IMG_4147-xs.png 300w ,https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/16/responsive/IMG_4147-sm.png 480w ,https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/16/responsive/IMG_4147-md.png 768w"  alt="" width="405" height="540"></figure>
<p>The post will be too long, if I talk about all the places in one go. So, wait for the next post. I will take you to Agra. </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>True happiness!</title>
        <author>
            <name>Shalini Chaudhary</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://soigne68.github.io/true-happiness.html"/>
        <id>https://soigne68.github.io/true-happiness.html</id>

        <updated>2022-08-15T22:16:05+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Happiness has different meanings for different people. Just like the sunrise and sunset kind of happiness. All of us can be happy if we centralise the core happiness within ourselves. There was a time that I was so naive that my happiness used to depend&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Happiness has different meanings for different people. Just like the sunrise and sunset kind of happiness. All of us can be happy if we centralise the core happiness within ourselves. There was a time that I was so naive that my happiness used to depend on the approval of others. Almost four decades of my life passed in this manner and then I realized that I had given undue importance to others. Slowly and gradually I picked up the pieces of my broken personality and tried to create a new 'me'. Now, I don't look for situations to make me happy. Rather I create my own happiness in my own way and have realized that this is the only way to be. No one should be given the authority to decide your happiness. Find happiness in yourself, in the things that make you happy, leave you contented. You will find that things have suddenly changed for better in your life. Try to remain receptive to what makes you feel happy and trust the process. You will surely reap benefits of your faith.</p>
<p>As born in a traditional family with 'zero to none' exposure to the outside world, it won't be an exaggeration to say that I knew nothing about the world. My childhood was laced with the proposition that people should be happy with you. Now, this was the major thing that shaped my personality. Being the youngest in the family, I always thought I must please my siblings, I must be good to my parents(which one should), I must make our guests feel at home and so on. You can very well understand that a child won't get any individuality or confidence in such circumstances. I tried to give my best in education and did my graduation with distinction. Now, came the time for post graduation and I was not allowed to go for a subject of my choice(as it was not available in my city). Well, being a subservient person, I followed what came to me. Adding more to the situation, I was married in the second semester of my further education. A new family, new people to deal with. I could have changed to a person who is aware of her requirements but as 'old habits die hard', I was the same in my new environment. And it had its toll on me in the best possible manner(ironically). I somehow completed my post graduation, did the degree course for teaching and started my career as a teacher. But then, God had His own designs and suddenly I was out of the 'Catch-22' situation and left to my own measures. To cut the long story short, I then chose the path which I had always in my mind and here I am with the first hand experience of the after effects of giving too much power and importance to others in your life.</p>
<p>The reason behind sharing my story is to bring home the clarity to my readers that it's your life. Take the reins in your hands and see the difference that you can make in your life. Loosen your attachments to the people around you, and you will naturally feel more connected to the person inside you. It's very important that we realise (sooner the better) the importance of being your own well-wisher first. In India, this realization is very important for the females, as they are taught to be tolerant, submissive and second to their counter-parts right from their early childhood. Knowing the pain of this, I try to give this understanding to all my acquaintances that no one is big or small. Both the genders have the equal right to carve a niche for themselves. The key to being happy is to know what to let go and what to accept in your life. It's a direction to your life not a destination. </p>
<p>I always practice gratitude, exercise, meditate and help others. This has helped me to move closer to my goal and find true happiness within myself. Planning a trip and spending quality time with family gives immense happiness.My recent trip to Mumbai and Jodhpur is a testament to this.</p>
<p> </p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/14/8FBF4D45-00A1-4FA3-832B-2B036BE2BA85.jpeg" sizes="(min-width: 61.3125em) 50vw, 100vw" srcset="https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/14/responsive/8FBF4D45-00A1-4FA3-832B-2B036BE2BA85-xs.jpeg 300w ,https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/14/responsive/8FBF4D45-00A1-4FA3-832B-2B036BE2BA85-sm.jpeg 480w ,https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/14/responsive/8FBF4D45-00A1-4FA3-832B-2B036BE2BA85-md.jpeg 768w"  alt="" width="323" height="404"></figure> <figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/14/90F8883E-8AB5-47D8-95D6-3B2EF322304E.jpeg" sizes="(min-width: 61.3125em) 50vw, 100vw" srcset="https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/14/responsive/90F8883E-8AB5-47D8-95D6-3B2EF322304E-xs.jpeg 300w ,https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/14/responsive/90F8883E-8AB5-47D8-95D6-3B2EF322304E-sm.jpeg 480w ,https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/14/responsive/90F8883E-8AB5-47D8-95D6-3B2EF322304E-md.jpeg 768w"  alt="" width="323" height="403"></figure>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/14/B564D115-424F-4D3A-AAAE-7228B3E934AF-4.heic" alt=""></figure><figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  style="color: var(--text-editor-body-color); font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);" src="https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/14/0354890E-DAC5-4AF0-B90E-4A13D22493C8.jpeg" sizes="(min-width: 61.3125em) 50vw, 100vw" srcset="https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/14/responsive/0354890E-DAC5-4AF0-B90E-4A13D22493C8-xs.jpeg 300w ,https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/14/responsive/0354890E-DAC5-4AF0-B90E-4A13D22493C8-sm.jpeg 480w ,https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/14/responsive/0354890E-DAC5-4AF0-B90E-4A13D22493C8-md.jpeg 768w"  alt="" width="324" height="431"></figure><figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  style="color: var(--text-editor-body-color); font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);" src="https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/14/B7E92574-8928-4A5E-ACAC-8AD589867A55.jpeg" sizes="(min-width: 61.3125em) 50vw, 100vw" srcset="https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/14/responsive/B7E92574-8928-4A5E-ACAC-8AD589867A55-xs.jpeg 300w ,https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/14/responsive/B7E92574-8928-4A5E-ACAC-8AD589867A55-sm.jpeg 480w ,https://soigne68.github.io/media/posts/14/responsive/B7E92574-8928-4A5E-ACAC-8AD589867A55-md.jpeg 768w"  alt="" width="323" height="431"></figure>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>About Shalini</title>
        <author>
            <name>Shalini Chaudhary</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://soigne68.github.io/about-shalini.html"/>
        <id>https://soigne68.github.io/about-shalini.html</id>

        <updated>2022-06-09T04:55:05+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    With a career spanning more than two decades, Shalini has touched the lives of thousands of students and hundreds of teachers in her quest to uplift and improve the quality of life of her community through education. Whether it be through her early days as&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With a career spanning more than two decades, Shalini has touched the lives of thousands of students and hundreds of teachers in her quest to uplift and improve the quality of life of her community through education. Whether it be through her early days as a junior teacher, her rise through TGT and PGT certifications, her role as a vice principal or a principal, she truly embodies the spirit of the word “educationist”. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Today, she runs her latest initiative, ‘Academia’ - an attempt to bring world class English education to Haryana.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Until 2021, she was actively involved in the growth and development of students in not only the academic field but also in the games field. Through an inspired combination of training, outreach programs, and general management, she managed to increase the students' interest in both of the fields. A national-level athlete for Haryana herself, she could manage to instill in her students a love for the outdoors. With her diligent tutelage, multiple children were selected for national level games. Her focus on teaching her cohort about sustainable living led her to working with the state government on tree planting initiatives and environmental preservation focused workshops at the school</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Her work was recognized with awards and recognition from the HRD Ministry, as well as frequent facilitations by local TV, radio, and newspaper entities. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Before taking up administration as her primary focus, Shalini was an English teacher at various prestigious organizations in Rajasthan and Haryana. She began her career in 1999 teaching junior classes foundations of the English language. After spending 4 years with young children, she realized that she can make a bigger impact to the general level of education and student growth by working with adolescents, teens, and pre-teens and began teaching at a renowned senior secondary school in Jodhpur. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In 2011, she moved back to her home state of Haryana, when she agreed to join O. P. Jindal Modern School, Hisar. She brought her experience and expertise from her previous work and set out to improving the educational foundations of the school. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In conclusion, while Shalini has held varied titles in varied geographies, her core mission has remained the same for the past 23 years – using education as a tool to improve the society from the ground up. As a student of English as well as Psychology, she understands that the best way to make systemic and lasting improvement is to teach the upcoming generation the best of what we know. That insight coupled with her incessant drive means that she has been delivering results in her field endlessly, and will continue to do so. Fiat lux. </span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Guidance and Counselling</title>
        <author>
            <name>Shalini Chaudhary</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://soigne68.github.io/guidance-and-counselling.html"/>
        <id>https://soigne68.github.io/guidance-and-counselling.html</id>

        <updated>2022-01-23T23:30:25+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Guidance and Counselling are very important tools to educate children and the schools have a tremendous responsibility of effectively bringing out the best in them. The need of guidance and counselling can be stated in simple terms to assist and help individuals adjust to their&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><span class="ILfuVd"><span class="hgKElc">Guidance and Counselling are very important tools to educate children and the schools have a tremendous responsibility of effectively bringing out the best in them. <span dir="ltr" role="presentation">The need of guidance and counselling </span><span dir="ltr" role="presentation">can be stated in simple terms to assist and help individuals adjust to their personal, </span><span dir="ltr" role="presentation">emotional, educational and occupational environment. Many a time, working parents are not able to give quality time to their children or pin point the root cause of their alienated behaviour. The role of guidance counsellors comes to the forefront in these situations. Guidance counsellors helps them to react to situations by developing new strategies and dealing with them in an efficacious manner. Counsellors render a professional service to the individuals who are facing some problem and needs help to overcome it. Guidance and counselling is oriented to help students understand themselves, become self-sufficient in making realistic and positive selections and grow in human relationships and concerns. Counselling sessions are a gradual process to mould and redirect children towards a brighter career. It also gives wings to the dreams of children through different vocational and career oriented guidance.</span></span></span></p>
<p>In the one-to-one counselling sessions, it's imperative that the child should feel safe and secure in the company of the counsellor and know that he/she is not being judged. The counsellor can ask questions but should not probe the child's privacy to an unacceptable level. Children are more comfortable in sharing their ideas with someone who is more objective  and not biased about them.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Responsibilities of a counsellor</span>-</p>
<ul>
<li>Facilitating the students in becoming more productive and dynamic members of the society</li>
<li>Providing emotional security and comfort</li>
<li>Helping in promoting insight</li>
<li>Leading to self awareness</li>
<li>Encouraging confidence</li>
<li>Ensuring confidentiality</li>
<li>Developing a positive self image</li>
<li>Building rapport</li>
</ul>
<p>A counsellor must show responsible and trustworthy behaviour with a positive and constructive problem solving approach. Their tone of voice should express interest and concern. Their body language, facial expressions, gestures and comments should be very structured and thoughtful. At no given point, should the child feel that they are being judged.</p>
<p>As far as guidance is concerned, young minds need it to polish their personality. Guidance sessions advise the children about selection of courses and different career opportunities, enabling them to make proper and informed choices for their future. It's important to prepare children for life after school and what to expect in the different fields they might opt for. Professional guidance helps the students to achieve their goals in the best possible manner. It not only helps them to take decisions pertaining to their career, but it also makes them confident and mentally prepares them for the challenges. They acquire knowledge, attitude and inter-personal skills to set their own goals and take their own decisions to achieve those goals. Along with their academic and career development, their social and personal development is also taken care of. Guidance and counselling makes students better informed individuals.</p>
<p>All over the world children are under extreme stress and anxiety due to performance issues. In India, the education system focusses more on quantitative learning with long school hours, heavy school bags and rote learning which leads to lesser creativity and innovation in the teaching and learning process. Now-a-days some educational institutions have come up with more technology based teaching, but there is a long way to go. Let us join hands to bring more quality to the education system with structured guidance and counselling to all the three stake holders of the education system, i.e. students, parents and teachers.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Year 2021</title>
        <author>
            <name>Shalini Chaudhary</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://soigne68.github.io/year-2021.html"/>
        <id>https://soigne68.github.io/year-2021.html</id>

        <updated>2021-12-31T21:23:03+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                     "Celebrate endings-for they precede new beginnings." Once again the time has come, when we sit back and introspect the year that is just slipping away from the calender. How fascinating is it that time passes by at its normal pace every single day and&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>                    <strong><em>"Celebrate endings-for they precede new beginnings."</em></strong></p>
<p>Once again the time has come, when we sit back and introspect the year that is just slipping away from the calender. How fascinating is it that time passes by at its normal pace every single day and once we reach to the end of the year, everyone comments,"Kaise beet gaya ek saal, pata hi nahin chala!"</p>
<p>The year 2021 came with its own challenges and promises. I sincerely thank God for blessing me and my loved ones with health and happiness and pray for this Heavenly benediction to continue in the years to come. I personally found a different meaning to my life this year. It was a rigmarole of events constantly happening almost the same way. In the past few years, my shift from a teacher to an administrator was exceptionally interesting. It was a great learning experience during all those years (on both sides of the table :)). But then, a desire to be my own master was always haunting me. Finally, the month of June 2021 witnessed the change and instead of being an employee, I became an employer. There was constant support from my family and friends and I sincerely thank them for their unflinching faith and confidence in me. It has given me a new level of understanding about my own capabilities.</p>
<p>As a country also, we have seen innumerable changes and events. There was a time when some people were battling for oxygen and some were hoarding it for emergent times. There were Samaritans who didn't let the faith in humanity die and worked tirelessly to bring hope and cheer in those desperate times. A big salute to all those people! Then we had the best Olympics tally of medals this year with a Gold Medal. India secured 47th position from the 65th position. Indeed a proud moment for all Indians! There were amazing contributions in the field of science and technology also with the unmanned space mission to the moon and launching of a nuclear submarine. The list is endless when we look towards the positive side and so is the list on the other side too. What matters is our perception! The year has given us a new insight with life changing experiences and we must step into 2022 with a new determination and hope. Many people change with the time and then there are a few who change the time. May we be the harbingers of change and bring glory to our being!</p>
<p>Let's move into 2022 with a resolution. A resolution to be more purposeful, humanitarian and loving. Work is important but it's also imperative to maintain our health. Keep scheduled working hours, visit your family, friends and invest in relations. Appreciate and enjoy the beauty of nature. We get this life once. Make the most of it.</p>
<p>Goodbye 2021! Welcome 2022....</p>
<p>Wish you all a very happy and prosperous new year! May it be filled with new adventures, happy times and good fortunes!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Show gratitude in all your actions!</title>
        <author>
            <name>Shalini Chaudhary</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://soigne68.github.io/show-gratitude-in-all-your-actions.html"/>
        <id>https://soigne68.github.io/show-gratitude-in-all-your-actions.html</id>

        <updated>2021-10-07T18:09:06+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    "Acknowledging the good that you already have in your life is the foundation for all abundance." I strongly believe in this quote because being thankful for what we have paves the way for more to come. Practicing this turns the excruciating pain of difficult times&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><em><strong>"Acknowledging the good that you already have in your life is the foundation for all abundance."</strong></em></p>
<p>I strongly believe in this quote because being thankful for what we have paves the way for more to come. Practicing this turns the excruciating pain of difficult times into tolerable ones. We shouldn't be deterred by the unfavourable events taking place in our lives, as these events only bring out our real resilient self into full projection. Even if the things are going wrong, set your vibrations into the tuning mode of your choice and see the difference. I know for a fact that it's easy said being done. But believe me, once you practice this art, you will find a different meaning to your life. </p>
<p>Let me give you a quick example. Around a decade ago, there came a night that seemed to loom larger then my existence. I was left devastated, broken and shattered by circumstances. I had my children with me and that was the only sunshine in the otherwise pitch dark scenario. I thanked God for what I had and tried to move on. I won't lie. I did cry in the initial phase but time is a great healer. It taught me that the  universe aligns us with people, things and situations. If there is something that is not required in our life, universe conspires to throw it out of the system. It may take time but it will definitely work for our betterment. Today, when I look back, I thank God for chartering this path for me. I bow my head in complete reverence to Him for blessing me with two mature individuals as my children. What troubled me didn't vanish suddenly, but I moved out of my tunnel vision of looking at things and tried to broaden my horizon into the periphery of my life where amazing things were happening in different manners.  We only need to arrange or orchestrate the things for desired results. There comes a time when you realise that everything that you've gone through was actually a blessing in disguise.</p>
<p>When we are building ourselves for a better tomorrow, there shouldn't be any time to dwell on the small little things actually petty things of yesterday. Make gratitude a fundamental feature of your existence. Right in the morning when you open your eyes, thank God for blessing you with a new day and promise yourself to do the best you can to make the day a remarkable one. When you sleep at night thank all those people in your heart, who helped you to achieve your goals during the day. It's a very healing exercise. If you can thank people in person, don't lose the chance. You never know you may not get the opportunity again. There goes a story about a man whose life was saved only because he had the habit of thanking the security guard before leaving for the day. One day he was locked in his office and couldn't reach anyone for help. The security guard raised an alarm about it because he hadn't seen him going and saved his life. </p>
<p>Every person is struggling his or her own battle. We should try to be kind and generous in all our ways and means. As we navigate the highs and lows in life, the love and compassion we share with others gives the direction and brightness to life. Let this journey be a journey of healing to make this world a better place to live. I thank you all for being there with me.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
