<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Shalini Chaudhary</title>
    <link href="https://soigne68.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://soigne68.github.io" />
    <updated>2020-06-25T09:04:10+05:30</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Shalini Chaudhary</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://soigne68.github.io</id>

    <entry>
        <title>It&#x27;s a mind game!</title>
        <author>
            <name>Shalini Chaudhary</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://soigne68.github.io/thought-process.html"/>
        <id>https://soigne68.github.io/thought-process.html</id>

        <updated>2020-06-25T08:59:05+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    There have been numerous talk shows/webinars these days on developing the skills to sustain hard times. All over the country, people have started talking about the importance of mental health and I feel that is a welcome move. People have come to understand that you&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>There have been numerous talk shows/webinars these days on developing the skills to sustain hard times. All over the country, people have started talking about the importance of mental health and I feel that is a welcome move. People have come to understand that you are no lesser a human being, if you take expert help to come out of your emotional problems. It's no more a taboo to talk about it. In this time of global pandemic, anxiety, loneliness and frustration are common everywhere, but we have to be ultimate survivors AND WE WILL BE. We have to look for solutions. Problems evolve us as human beings and push us towards a better version of ourselves. What is important in life is that, how we deal with them? What is the meaning we are giving to the problem? If we bow down and surrender, it will grow exponentially and soon we will be the victim of self-sabotage. Each and every thing that we possess can be taken away from us, but our real treasure--our power of thinking and decision making can not be snatched. Even if things go to ashes, and there seems no hope of revival...we can rise from the dust, just like the mythological phoenix. We can bring a paradigm shift in the existing scenario by trying to create positive vibes...first within ourselves and then spreading it in the society at large. </p>
<p>If we wish to achieve someting in our life. then nothing can deter us. We need to invest our time, mind and energy. We need to train our belief system, because belief shapes our behaviour and behaviour makes the destiny. Be in the company of enthusiastic people, who speak good, practice good and sprinkle the charm of their goodness everywhere. I had read a book (Man's search for meaning) by Dr Viktor Frankl, where he has enumerated the various hardships he had to face in the Nazi concentration camp, during the World War II. He was resilient and visualised a better tomorrow. And he did survive to tell his part of the success story to the world. There are other examples also, where we find exceptional courage and determination to excel. Mountaineer Arunima Sinha is the most glaring example. She was lying on the railway track for the whole night in the most deplorable condition, but her determination was stronger then the problems, and inspite of being amputated below the knee and having a prosthetic leg, she achieved her dream of hoisting national flag on Mount Everest. When people can come out from such dire situations, then it's not difficult for us too. We just have to maintain hygiene, keep social distance and remain at home. This shall also pass.</p>
<p>I have realised that there are unlimited possibilities to recreate, reinvent and reenergise ourselves in this Lockdown period. All we have to do is to decide for a better tomorrow. Take this time as a time to put reset button. I feel that if we have the half glass full attitude, then we we will be able to sail through all odds. Don't feel scared with the magnanimity of the problem, rather face it head on and I am sure you will succeed. Be confident about yourself, plan and priortise your goals, set a timeline and work towards it. There cannot be any force stopping you to achieve your dreams.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>A tiny step  </title>
        <author>
            <name>Shalini Chaudhary</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://soigne68.github.io/a-tiny-step.html"/>
        <id>https://soigne68.github.io/a-tiny-step.html</id>

        <updated>2020-04-07T07:48:36+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    The journey of a thousand miles begins with a single step, and here I am, taking a tiny step towards the fulfilment of my long cherished dream of writing a blog. I was busy in the humdrum of life and found no time suitable to&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>The journey of a thousand miles begins with a single step, and here I am, taking a tiny step towards the fulfilment of my long cherished dream of writing a blog.</p>
<p>I was busy in the humdrum of life and found no time suitable to pursue my dreams. These days, due to COVID-19 outbreak, life has come to a standstill.This time has forcibly taught us the importance of things that we had taken for granted. Family relations were dying down, the rich were getting richer and the life of poor was going down the drain. Now, this tiny virus has shown its might and told us that we are just a speck of dust in the hands of nature. Nature views us all with the same glass.</p>
<p>True, we are at home, just blocked from the outside world. But, isn't it beautiful? A magnificent realization has dawned upon us. All  hatred and spite has been shown the door and we are trying to be as productive, as we can, in these trying times. As parents and teachers, we are struggling hard to provide the best education to our children. We have come out from the belief that learning requires a pre-designated place called school/college, and can happen at home also. Constantly, I am receiving messages from parents showing their contentment in being an active participant in their child's education, They are realising the importance of schools and the plethora of activities that take place there, for the holistic development of their children. I feel the understanding between parents and teachers will improve exponentially.</p>
<p>Time to time, we are getting messages from various sectors, telling us the ways and means to utilise the time productively. Many online courses are free of charge during this 'Lock down period'. We must understand that education is not merely subject knowledge. It also requires practical hands on experience to deal with real life issues. Children should be taught basic culinary skills, plumbing, cleaning and dusting etc.  This time shall pass, but God forbid, if something like this happens again, at least we will be better prepared. We must learn from the lessons that it has taught. Quite unexpectedly, this tiny virus has taken over the mankind in the most brutal manner. Hundreds and thousands of people are dying but many more are surviving also. Let's all be very resilient and strong, within ourselves, and pledge to come out victorious from this 21 day isolation period.</p>
<p>This inconvenient time can be called as a 'golden chance' to visit the forgotten era and bring out the pearls from the recesses of time.This is the time to go with in, meditate and introspect and try to heal the battered soul. With social distancing, we can unite with ourselves, with people who should matter the most in our lives(referring to family members) and can plan for a better tomorrow. Everyone had been running around to amass more and more materialistic pleasures not only for themselves but for generations to come, as if they would be mutants and incompetent to feed for themselves.</p>
<p>There should be an end to all this. The world is a beautiful plce to live in. Let's all take a vow to give more quality time to our family members, protect each other and the Mother Earth for a better tomorrow. Let's imbibe gratitude to be our way of life and thank all those who are tirelessly working, so that we may live in peace. My salute to all the health officials, police department, emergency services personnel, and many unsung heroes without whom, it would have been a nightmare.</p>
<p>This being my first post, I would like to specially mention and thank my son, Abhishek, who created this platform for me, and my daughter, Aditi, who was a constant support to me. Without their contribution, my dream would not have seen the light of the day. </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
